so here we have an example of Young's
double slit experiment um the problem
states that the distance between the two
slits as indicated here in the diagram
is 03 millimeters I haded that in blue
for you and it does say that it's a
second order bright Fringe that's being
observed and then the angle between the
zero uh m equal to zero or the central
Fringe to the second or the right Fringe
is 215° again as shown here in the
diagram and it wants us to find the
wavelength of the light that's coming in
so to do uh so before you proceed uh you
should definitely scope out units uh
again I notic here this is given in
millimeters uh I would like to tell you
to convert everything to meters first
this way you know naturally things will
cancel out and then if you need to
convert at the very end to whatever
units they're asking for then do so at
the very end in this case I can see that
it wants it in nanometer so I know I
have to convert a little bit at the very
end uh so at to start I'll go ahead and
convert the distance between the two
slits in Mill millimeters to meters the
conversion factor between meters to
millimeters shown here on the screen for
every 1 meter there's 1,000 millimeters
uh so Place stuff in the right order and
then millimeters is going to cancel out
uh in the numerator denominator there
and if you do the calculator work
that'll give you 3.01 105 meters so now
that that's done uh we can go ahead and
proceed we want to go ahead and use
Young's doubleit function for
constructive interference because the
problem states that it is a bright
Fringe where m is equal to two uh so
we'll go ahead and bust this out again D
is the distance between the the slits uh
Theta is the angle between uh the or
Central bright frence and the second
order bright frence here and M we know
what m is and I'll get to that in just a
second okay but it's important to keep
the in mind that M must be 0 1 2 3 or
four according to Young's dite function
it cannot be like a 0.5 or 1.5 so M must
be any whole number uh
so as you can see highlighted there it
say the second order bright Fringe so
therefore m is two so even if the
problem doesn't give you like for
example in the parentheses m is equal to
2 uh they do expect for you to interpret
this information and know what value of
M to use so in this case it's pretty
straightforward we know that D is given
to us as 3.01 105 so we can substitute
that for there we know that from the
statement m is two so we can just
substitute uh m in the denominator uh
for value of two from here everything we
do know is calculator work time so 3.0 *
5 m Time s of 25 / 2 if you punch all
that in your calculator carefully you
should get a result of 5.6 T 107 M okay
but again you notice here the answer
here is in meters the question asked for
uh the wavelength and nanometers so we
just have to convert meters to
nanometers and that's pretty easy to do
uh so start with the uh statement 5.6 M7
meters times it again it's important
that you place the conversion factor
correctly here you want to put meters on
the bottom because you started off
meters so meter here is going to cancel
with meters in the denominator and that
leaves you with the units of nanometer
and in case you don't know for every one
meter there's 10 to the 9th nanometers
so if you do that properly the final
outcome will come out to be about
nanometers okay other than that it's
pretty straight for a problem okay all
right don't be whacked stay
nerdy